RG 181, Department of Public Works
Connecticut State Library
Department of Public Works records
1931-2011, bulk 1951-2011
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Dept. of Public Works
77.25 cubic feet
Materials in the collection include architectural plans and specifications for for State Captiol maintenance and repair projects, photographs of various Public Works projects, groundbreaking and dedication programs, and files documenting the Home Ownership Program.
RG181
Multiple
Historical Note
1951, January 3, Public Act 50-4, Public Works Department established
1977, October 1, Public Act 77-614, Public Works Department becomes the Bureau of Public Works within the Department of Administrative Services
1987, July 1, Public Act 87-496, An independent Department of Public Works is reestablished
2011, July 1, Public Act 11-51, Department of Public Works eliminated; construction responsibilities transferred to the new Department of Construction Services; all other functions transferred to Department of Administrative Services
See also the brief description of the.
Scope and Content
Series 1. Drawings and Specifications, 1938-1973, bulk 1952-1973 pertain to projects at the State Capitol.
Series 2. Photographs, 1972-2011 depict completed construction projects, groundbreakings, ribbon cuttings, and Dept. of Public Works events.
Series 3. Home Ownership Program, 1951-1962 contains mortgage loan files related to the program.
Series 4. Groundbreaking and Dedication Programs, 1991-2011 document the order of exercises for the groundbreaking for and the dedication of completed construction projects.
Series 5. Videos, 1985-2004 include videos of Gampel Pavillion at the University of Connecticut and the dedication of the University of Connecticut Law School Library.
Series 6. News Clippings, 1931 consists solely of a copy of the Hartford Times, Second Section (November 28, 1931), concerning the opening of the State Office Buillding.
Arrangement
Series 1. Drawings and Specifications, 1952-1973
Series 2. Photographs, 1972-2011
Series 3. Home Ownership Program, 1951-1962
Series 4. Groundbreaking and Dedication Programs, 1991-2011
Series 5. Videos, 1985-2004
Series 6. News Clippings, 1931
Related Material
, Connecticut State Library.
Index Terms
Organizations:
Connecticut. Dept. of Public Works; Connecticut. Public Works Dept.
Subjects:
Connecticut. Dept. of Public Works -- Records and correspondence; Connecticut. Public Works Dept. -- Records and correspondence; Connecticut State Capitol (Hartford, Conn.) -- Maintenance and repair; Housing -- Connecticut; Public buildings -- Connecticut -- Design and construction; Public works -- Connecticut
Document Types:
Application forms; Blueprints (reprographic copies); Correspondence; Photographs; Programs (documents); Specifications; Videocassettes
Restrictions on Access
Some of these records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Provenance
Accessions were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on the following dates:
1984-110: 1984 (exact date not known)
1989-001: 1989 (exact date not known)
1992-076: June 4, 1992
2011-120: April 6, 2011
2013-022: December 18, 2012
2013-043: April 16, 2013
Container List
- Series 1. Drawings and Specifications, 1952-1973
  - State Capitol projects, 1952-1973; 1984-110
    A list in the first folder titled "Drawings from Capitol Basement" lists 63 items. Numbers given below correspond to the item on the list. Not all items on the list are present. The location of the items not included here is not known.
    - List (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 36. Protective railings and screens, 1965 February 16 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 38. Repair, plaster, and paint upper walls of light wells, 1964 July 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 39. Refinish gold dome, 1971 August 5 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 40. Exterior lighting, 1971 August 5 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 41. Lighting of Capitol dome, 1971 January - April; 2 copies (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
    - 42. Structural repairs, 1949 July 29 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 44. Public address and paging system, House of Representatives, 1956 October 30 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 45. Fixtures and wiring, public areas, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 46. Locker plans, House coat rooms, 1956 May (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 47. Snow guards for Captiol roof, 1964 July (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - 48. Repairs to Connecticut State Capitol, 1959r July 29 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - 49. Protective railings and screens, 1965 February 16 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - 50. First floor paging ststen, 1956 July 26; 3 copies (Box 1, Folder 15-17)
    - 51. Paint and repair all exteriror windows, 1961 August 10 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - 52. Conversion of storage area to hearing room, 1958 November (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - 53. Misc. alterations to State Capitol, 1962 November 15 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - 54. Refinishing exterior doors, 1956 March (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - 55. Misc. accident reports, 1952,1955-1966, undated (Box 1, Folder 22-28)
    - 55. Misc. accident reports, blank forms, undated (Box 1, Folder 29-31)
    - 56. Sidewalks, State Capitol, Library, Office Building areas, 1962 December (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - 57. Sidewalk repairs, 1961 January 17 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - 58. Repair boiler setting, 1956 August (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - 59. State Office Building, floor plan, 1969 June 18 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - 60. Replace wood platforms, 1973 November 28 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - 61. Convert Room 214 to women's rest room, 1962 July (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - 62. Misc. memos, use of hearing rooms, parking, etc., 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - 63. Refinishing exterior doors, 1956 March (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Series 2. Photographs, 1972-2011
  - Photographic negatives, 1972-1985; 1989-001; 1.75 cubic feet (3 boxes)
    Unprocessed.
  - Completed projects, 1987-2008; 2011-120; 100 photographs on foam boards (24 cubic feet), 20 in. x 30 in.
  - Completed projects, groundbreakings, and ribbon cuttings, 1988-2011, undated; 2013-022
    Boxes 1-5 contain 8 in. x 10 in. prints. Box 6 contains snapshots.
    - 1988-2001 (Box 1)
    - 2002-2003 (Box 2)
    - 2004-2006 (Box 3)
    - 2007-2011, undated (Box 4)
    - undated (Box 5)
      Unlabeled and loose photographs are included in this box.
    - 1990-1998 (Box 6)
- Series 3. Home Ownership Program, 1951-1962; 24 cubic feet; 1992-076
  - Loans 1 - 298, 1951-1960 (Box 1)
  - Loans 311 - 615, 1951-1960 (Box 2)
  - Loans 657 - 999, 1951-1960 (Box 3)
  - Loans 1014 - 1483, 1951-1960 (Box 4)
  - Loans 1538 - 1848, 1951-1960 (Box 5)
  - Loans 1911 - 2376, 1951-1960 (Box 6)
  - Loans 2408 - 2985, 1951-1960 (Box 7)
  - Loans 3007 - 3681, 1951-1960 (Box 8)
  - Loans 3708 - 4279, 1951-1960 (Box 9)
  - Loans 4229 - 5094, 1951-1960 (Box 10)
  - Loans 5114 - 6015, 1951-1960 (Box 11)
  - Loans V21 - V875, 1955, 1961-1962 (Box 12)
  - Loans V894 - V1592, 1961-1962 (Box 13)
  - Loans V1600 - V2302, V2285, V2307, 1960-1962 (Box 14)
  - Loans V2337 - V3460, V2548, 1959, 1961-1962 (Box 15)
  - Loans V3468 - V4734, V2712, V4492, 1957, 1961-1962 (Box 6)
  - Loans V4738 - V5630, V5506, V5505, V5396, 1956, 1959-1962 (Box 17)
  - Loans V - V6026, 1961-1962 (Box 18)
- Series 4. Groundbreaking and Dedication Programs, 1991-2011; 2013-022
  - 1991-2011 (Box 7, Folder 1-7)
  - Duplicates, 1991-2010 (Box 7, Folder 8-15)
- Series 5. Videos, 1985-2004; 2013-022
  - Video cassette tapes, 1988-2004 (Box 8)
  - Beta max, 1985-1993 (Box 9)
- Series 6. News Clippings, 1931
  - Hartford Times, 1931 November 28; 2013-043 (Box Item 1)
    Second Section. "New State Office Building Costing Over $2,000,000 Distinctive for Simplicity, Practicability and Strength."
    This item is RESTRICTED due to fragile condition.